official mumbo for mare t-shirts are now
available link in the description and a
bit more on that later
that's right we're back in another
episode
of
hermitcraft
i don't know why i'm doing this in
today's episode
we are going to be doing
lots of things in the base i have been
preparing my new stock for the barge one
of which is empty maps and of course
item frames but these are
more expensive than you might think
they cost quite a lot scar says
g-man you got any tnt
actually
i do that's funny he should mention it
because i have just been trying to stock
up some tnt for the barge if he needs to
blow something up i'm up for it i need
to make a boom boom should use the
toilet then shouldn't you
i don't know if this is going to be
enough but i mean that's quite a lot of
tnt
where is he come over to my new build i
don't know where his new build is
it's behind my base now okay so what
does he mean by behind because this
doesn't have a front
so behind his bases mumbo behind his
base is ischael's base behind his base
is stress's face and behind his face is
my base
what's behind it it must be this way
then literally must be this way because
he is sandwiched in i think oh
goodness
yeah there he is
what is he doing
a giant
circle
[Laughter]
there he is hello good sir
hello what is going on oh my goodness
look at that drill i didn't even see the
drill it has a name oh uh it's a big bud
i was gonna say big ben
big
yeah it's big bud he does what big bud
likes to do and that's drill um this is
the giant big dig project the sequel and
uh we're going to the nether get those
1.16 boxes going to be amazing yeah i
bought i brought is this enough it's
quite a lot
that's gonna be awesome um hold on i
just have something to throw to you just
uh just i'm gonna throw a couple of
those your way
[Applause]
you wanna
what do you think a little bit better
than the uh the dark oak sign dude look
at your vote for scar thing someone's
like
someone's straight up there on the map
what's going on over there
someone's on your map
someone is they're messing with it this
tnt what are your thoughts on making a
little boom boom happen here i'm not an
official boomer like i have nothing to
do with the boomers so i'm like a
discount boomer i'll blow anything up
for one diamond i just like blowing
stuff up um how about one of these
beautiful beautiful signs i've already i
already got some of these and i don't
want concrete do you think i need them
dude one diamond come on just a diamond
i don't think oh blue terracotta there
it is it's
a little darker diamond i'm not darker
diamond i'm not being unreasonable here
oh don't shoot oh you want to give me
that you wanna give me that diamond
yes there you go how how how big a boom
boom you want
as big as boom boom we can make all
right we're gonna use all of this might
crash the server just just i i i need
you to sign a waivers form saying that
the agreement holds no responsibility
for death of a server player or any
builds in the vicinity i'm gonna need
that in writing from you is that all
right
i wrote it on the shulker box or i'll
send it to you officially right okay
cool because this could this could end
badly in fact it probably will end badly
because i don't i don't know restraint
all right let's go are you ready scar
that's five stacks of tnt down there it
doesn't look like it does it there's
just this little ignition popping out
the top
all right i got my i got my bow i got my
boat here hit it with the flame bow
hit it with the flame bow
hit it with the flame though i got this
i got it how is anyone going to vote for
mayor
how is anyone going to support you to be
there
oh my goodness
oh amazing
that was actually extremely successful
wow
oh oh oh oh there's so many bad things
down here
oh get it get out of there scott i got
along with you
yes things never go well
this has created a perfect crater
the start of the big dig
this is amazing well thank you you i
mean i mean maybe we should just become
the boomers the boomers too competition
discount boomer one diamond i'll blow it
up ah what world
no no no things aren't going well
no grinding
that's okay that that's how good things
normally go
oh no
that was hilarious that last thing that
happened to scar was amazing in fact i
actually had the whole thing on replay
mod let's watch an instant replay of
this because it is phenomenal i don't
know how scar does this i really don't
so take a look at this he's he's aggro
an enderman which is following him which
forces him to abandon ship and go down
he then hits a couple of blocks
panics
uses them and goes full belt into two
creepers which promptly explode
and there he goes
absolutely brilliant i can't even
remember what i was doing i was
producing a bunch of stuff for the barge
actually i have a lot of crafting to do
i have actually made a decent amount of
empty maps now and that actually got me
thinking i want to i want to produce
some maps of this area kind of get a a
nice a nice coverage wow that's not what
i expected that to look like know what
let's get a let's get a decent map of
this entire area and save it so that
we've got like a timestamp of what this
used to look like i probably should have
done this right at the start of the
season to be honest it's maybe a little
bit late now but we're gonna do it
anyway i've got a bunch of maps not a
complete one but i'm thinking
these are pretty empty spaces on the
wall i could use these as like time
stamps every few months we could update
these so i need to lock these to start
with and then i think we could probably
put together a really nice map area
to show
the whole thing i definitely won't be
doing this again anytime soon so this is
the first one i kind of wish i did this
at the start of the season and this was
number two
but this is number one because i only
just thought of this but in a few months
time we can put another there another
there and by the end of the season we
could have four different timestamps of
this area
and i think this is a really good map it
shows an awful lot of things obviously
here we have
my base and it is a lot brighter with
that prismarine color but you can see
it's definitely not done it's very messy
around it i've locked all of these maps
then to the north we've got scars base
with all his village we've got his en
his nether portal the creeper farm and
then north of that we have mumbo's
unfinished base we've got the unfinished
omega tree
e
stresses base down to the south a little
bit and then a new addition to the
jungle slash mesa area is rendog he is
now
i think officially part of our little
crew here in the jungle
we got iskall's little hobbit hole to
the north
and then we've got scars new venture
that we just exploded a crater inside
and then there is big ben his little
drill uh big bud i think big ben that is
a way better name but there we have it
one big hole here with absolutely
nothing in it potentially the location
of a project how cool is this
gives you a real idea of where
everything is because it must be hard
when you watch the videos to know
exactly where all this is but i won't be
doing this again anytime soon and i have
christened this hermitcraft season 7
jungle gang episode 25 green and the
date
absolutely amazing
now what we're going to do is very
speedily craft all of this stuff up
which i've prepared for the barge so i
can get some more stock in there to make
some more diamonds of course crafting
crafting crafting crafting crafting
crafting up all the things crafting
crafting crafting crafting what a boring
scene crafting crafting crafting very
very speedy crafting crafting crafting
we're gonna craft more crafting crafting
crafting crafting crafting crafting
crafting crafting crafting for four
hours more and we are done these are
extremely high item values each one is a
stack of leather
and a stack of logs plus all the
crafting nonsense that you just saw and
then empty maps crafting up compass for
iron oh it's it's these are very high
value items and i expect them to do very
well at the shop which we can go and
have a look at right now
oh my every time you come to the
shopping district there's something new
to see what is this excalibur level
sword doing in the shopping district
sponsored by the false vermeer campaign
opening soon grumbot we need to step up
our game
and what's this
the gorgeous intelligent fountain of
truth take a gorgeous wish stone and
rename it to your mayoral wish then
throw it in the fountain i wish for
mumbo to be mayor throw it in
and down it goes
i hope my wish comes true appreciation
stone and a diamond this could be a
win-win
[Laughter]
once again i got completely distracted
and let's go and take a look at the
polling situation apparently you can
support more than one person i'm not
sure how that works because then you get
this situation where every
everyone's equal at the moment i kind of
like that it's quite funny
oh all except doc but i haven't seen him
online in a while
things are about to get a lot more
interesting anyway i keep getting
distracted i need to set up a place for
these at the end
literally the last two spots now filled
item frames and empty maps and we've got
some sails
ah we are out of sand and i assume we
are mega out of gravel as well okay so
for empty maps considering how much has
to go into an empty map it is four
diamonds per stack i think it's quite
justified and what really makes it more
justified is the the amount of time it
takes to craft that stuff up
and the same with here but it is three
diamonds a stack there we go
not too bad
i really really love the barge it's like
my favorite it's my one and only shop
and it is definitely my baby it is it
has grown up and it still has a little
ways to go
but the more stock i add the harder and
harder it is to keep stocked so now
we have to go on a little grind session
to get some gravel
and some sand my favorite
so let's go on a little time-lapse
adventure
for the grind
for the grind yay grinding
[Music]
four fresh boxes of sand four fresh
boxes of gravel and we are officially
stocked up in here
now i actually want to head over to
legrumbot because i have
a little question for him and it regards
wait a second
that wasn't there before no
well i i guess we'll put we'll keep that
there to show who the competition is
we'll put it upside down though
the question i have is in regards
to
the button
now we all know that the button died i
lost my gauntlet it was a whole thing
but the grumbot being the ultimate ai
that it is should know
what happened to it obviously i mean
obviously it broke but i need a diamond
why did mumbo make this so that you have
to pay for it but i want to know who was
responsible what happened
to
the button
what happened to the button grumbot
flood those mayoral reservoirs
and what do we get
do we get an answer i don't know if he
ever doesn't answer i think he always
gives an answer
yep there it is
it it
it died
well you're not wrong let's do this
again
how did it die
how did it die we need to be a bit more
specific this time if we want to get a
if we want to get a good answer out
grumbot
come on how did how did the button die
you must know
yeah he knows
and
he's sad
why are you sad crumble
oh no
one must die so another can live what on
earth what did you do grumba what did
did you do this i don't i'm not gonna
you know what i'm not gonna even ask
another question about that so my next
question is what do i do
now what do i do now grambot
tell me
i don't know if i actually have to press
all the buttons but i think i do what do
you think grumbot you got an answer for
me what do we do in the mayor campaign
oh he's got an answer where mumbo for
mayor sorry wear mumbo
where as in as in wear it that's totally
right we have mumbo for mare
t-shirts and i guess i should actually
put one on in game as well as real life
so
i'm gonna get changed into my uh mumbo
for mere skin check it out my own
mumbo for mayor t-shirt in minecraft
okay look listen there's not enough
pixels on a minecraft character to make
this t-shirt work so you get three lines
just pretend that those three lines with
three red lines say mumbo former
imagination
there's a link down below if you want to
get yourself a mumbo former t-shirt and
here's me wearing one all right now that
we're wearing our mumbo female t-shirt
it is time to go back to the base now
there's actually something i really want
to try and it's a little bit cheeky but
i think it could be fun towards the end
of every episode or at least until he
notices what i want to do is grab a
block any block
it doesn't really matter what and i want
to add it to mumbo jumbo's base not
really on the outside here but somewhere
somewhere in his inner oh he's there oh
he just logged in oh that's terrible
timing oh no this just this just got a
lot harder maybe i should come back
later
what are the odds come on i just wanted
to i just wanted to sneak in your base
so
he's right there
oh there's no way for me to land
so we kind of started this in his
industrial district we changed one of
the iron golem heads into agreeing head
and
successfully so
he didn't notice at all now that was
quite a big change but what i'm thinking
is we just add one
block
every now and again to his base
until he notices
now if we do this correctly
and you guys keep it quiet he may never
notice anything and by and and within a
few weeks he'll have loads of random
stuff in there but i don't see how i'm
going to get in while he's just there he
i mean if he sees if he sees me doing it
then he's going to suspect something yes
yes yes yes yes yes
oh no he's coming back
he's coming back
uh-oh i think i've been rambled oh my
how has he not seen me
i don't know what he's doing but mumbo's
been like jumping up and down for about
five minutes now i don't know what i'm
i'm too i'm i i'm literally far too deep
into this now to turn around and fly
away because then he'll definitely see
me
i feel like i've just got to wait this
out
this was a terrible decision
you see you can see him bouncing around
above me
why did i decide to do this i just
wanted to add a lantern to his base
without him noticing
and now i'm stuck in this bizarre
situation where i'm hiding from him i
could just
what is he up to
and here we see
the mumbo jumbo in his natural habitat
seemingly thinking as he bounces up and
down with the use
of his wings this behavior has baffled
scientists and hermits alike
for many generations the behavior of a
mumbo jumbo has come to be regarded as
one of the most
strange actions that can be had by any
living creature
do you think i should go for it he is
busy facing that way
but if he turns around the game's up
we go
yes
no fall damage
success
okay
all we need to do now
is put this lantern
and it is complete this has been the
most insane
insane thing
[Laughter]
oh no
any noise could any noise could be bad
now
all right i'm gonna put the lantern
here right here he may notice it he may
not but i if i know mumbo jumbo at all
he'll just accept that this is there if
you see this in a mumbo jumbo video you
can all wink and no but please
don't put him onto this
i went through too much effort to sneak
in here i don't even know why i'm doing
this
but this is just the beginning okay it's
only it's a lantern now but then it's a
green head behind there and then it's a
cow head on there and then it's another
block that's removed you know just
changes every now and again
is it safe
it's still there okay the next problem
is how on earth do i get out of here i
see no way out please don't come down
here i've done some pretty stupid things
in this server but this is by far the
stupidest and
i don't even need to hide that much
why am i so scared of being caught
lighting up his base
i just don't want him to know i'm here
okay
he logged in at such a bad time
i've got myself into quite the pickle
here i can't see a way out without
making a noise
[Music]
he's caught me why is he gone why
all of that just to be rumbled instantly
i i lost my call i could have maybe got
away with it okay so he may have seen me
in the base but the lantern's there now
next episode we'll put another block and
the episode after that we'll put another
block the second he notices even one of
them
the game is up okay so if you let him
know game over like episode one game
over
mumbo didn't even say anything by the
way he's just like oh green just green
just being green anyway
mega distraction from what i that was
that i think that was me basically
putting off having to do any work on my
base now that was that was me
trying to get out of some work i don't
really feel like doing a lot of progress
on this today if i'm honest you can only
do work on a project so much but what i
will do is just a tiny bit of detailing
here that i have been putting off it
won't take too long but this sort of
thing i don't know why i'm struggling to
do it but we'll we're just going to get
this done it's not going to take too
long but let's uh let's just get some
progress done on the base just to tick
that box and make a little bit more
progress than i have been and stop
messing around with mumbo jumbo
[Music]
like i said a very small amount of work
but this kind of detailing does take
some time at least it's actually
symmetrical now
at least it's symmetrical now because
there was no detailing here before but
there is on the other side so hopefully
soon i can
i can muster all the energy i have to
just get this done detailing two block
diagonals is so difficult and time
consuming and frustrating because you
end up with these weird
weird little bits that just don't quite
fit but don't worry we'll get there in
the end one way or another this
mansion's getting done little by little
working on projects like this can be
really really difficult because you've
got to make them look good and if i just
went nuts on this go in blind just do my
thing just start you know detailing it
could go wrong and then i could have
wasted a lot of time right
so what we do is we go into creative
mode on a private server and we try and
figure out exactly what we want this to
look like and then we remake it here now
the problem is the problem is even with
all the tools like world edit and all
that kind of stuff it still takes almost
a full day just to plan and to
experiment and get the shape right in a
creative world a fun fact about this
mansion is it took me two full days just
to come up with the basic design of just
this top half here
none of this was in the original design
but it took me two days
just to come up with that so for every
time you see me working on this there
was hours behind the scenes trying to
get it absolutely perfect
and that's what's due next so the
episode after this one may take a little
longer because i need to really sit down
and figure out what we're gonna put on
here sometimes it comes easier than
others sometimes you hit a block in the
road but i'm afraid that is all we have
time for
today
and i actually i'm gonna ask something
that i never normally ask now i know a
lot of you may not actually reach the
end of the video because you know it's
the end but i'm gonna say it if you do
like the video please consider
subscribing to the channel and doing all
those youtubey things like hitting the
bell anyway thank you very much for
watching i hope you enjoyed this episode
let me know what you thought in the
comments below and there is a link to
the mumbo former t-shirts in the
description have a look and see if you
want to support us thank you very much
for watching and good bye
oh this could be dangerous
bale